Finding aid for the Paul Monette papers, 1945-1995 LSC.1707
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 4: Writings
  - Subseries 4.5: Fan Mail and Miscellaneous
    - A Rock and a Hard Place: One Boy's Triumphant Story: Foreword: Letter from Richard Labonte (March 1993), note from Irvin Sasaki (July 1993) encloses Gregory House Gazette no.210, with photocopy of PM's letter to IS (June 28, 1993) discussing reception of Johnson's work., March 26 and July 7, 1993. (Box 21, Folder 15)
      Labonte writes after reading A Rock and a Hard Place and PM's introduction in galleys.
    - Requests for Publications: From Various Persons: Letters Received, 1989-1994. (Box 47, Folder 20)
      Brian Bouldrey (for Wrestling with the Angel, no contribution by PM), Kenneth Hanes, Michael Klein, Edward Osowski.
    - Requests for Publicity Quotations: From Various Persons: Letters Received: From Katherine V. Forrest, Linda Gray Sexton, etc., 1993-1994. (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Requests for Publicity Quotations: From Various Persons: Letters Received: Unknown if quotations used., 1993. (Box 47, Folder 22)
    - Criticism: Letters and enclosures of critiques of PM's work., 1993-1995 and n.d.; Primarily photocopies. (Box 47, Folder 25)
      Includes critques from: Joseph Cady, John Clum, Ed Madden, Deborah Nelson, David Roman, Sharon Warner.
    - Fan Mail, n.d. / v.d. (Box 25, Folder 16-17)
    - Fan Mail, n.d. / v.d. (Box 26, Folder 1-3)
    - Fan Mail: Unanswered., n.d. / v.d. (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
    - Fan mail. Enclosing Works: Folder 1 of 2., n.d. / v.d. (Box 34, Folder 1)
      Includes letters from: John D. Adams, Edisol Dotson, Peter Schellin. See also: Files in Biographical Group of papers, writers enclosing mss. etc.
    - Fan mail. Enclosing Works: Folder 2 of 2., n.d. / v.d. (Box 34, Folder 2)
      Includes letters from: Otis Charles, Eric A. Gordon (refers also to PM's speech at Southern California Library dinner), Ed Madden.
    - Fan Mail: Friends of friends., n.d. / v.d. (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Fan Mail: Former students., n.d. / v.d. (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Fan Mail: Replies from PM., June 1990. (Box 34, Folder 10)
      Photocopy of letter sent to fan.
    - Fan Mail: Yale classmates., n.d. / v.d. (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Fan Mail: UCLA speech / address, printed in Frontiers., n.d. / v.d. (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Editorial Piece, Poems, and Interview: In Magazines, 1988-1995 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Publicity Quotations: For: Decade Dance: For Michael Lassell., 1990. (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Dedications: Articles: Love Sick by Michael Lassell., February 14, 1992. (Box 19, Folder 35)
      For his talent, intelligence, industry, wit and compassion; for his dogged romanticism, consummate hospitality and limitless friendship....
    - 38 5.25 inch floppy disks (mostly containing screenplay drafts, some poems); 2 VHS Tapes (first cut of "Brink of Summer's End" and recording of a 1994 activists' dinner); and 2 unidentified CDs and 1 DVD (possibly materials for the UCLA Special Collection's 2005 tribute)., after 1980 (Box 71)
      Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
- Series 5: Roger Horwitz Papers
  - Trave: Journal: Western Europe: Montreal, Liverpool, London, Dover, Ostend, Brussels, Amsterdam, Koln, Wiesbaden [listed in front; were tours elsewhere: Lucerne, Venice, Florence, Assisi, Rome, Italian Riviera, Nice, Paris]: Entries in bound diary: My Holiday Abroad., July-August 1957.; 1 small volume. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    Started from Chicago July 4, 1957, returned to Chicago August 15, 1957. Roger David Horwitz.
  - Travel/Residence: Journal: France (Paris): Also contains letters (unsent?), etc., 1960-.; Typescript (primarily), holograph on loose leaves. (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Travel/Residence: Journal: France (Paris): Transcription., November 2, 1960-August 10, 1961.; Typescript. (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Travel/Residence: Journal With Poems on Loose Leaves: Traveling from France (Paris): Sample entries: Paris to Rome, May 16, 1961, Athens May 17, 1961 ... (Box 41, Folder 4)
    In composition book: Librairie-Papeterie Joseph Gibert. Cf. Borrowed Time.
  - Travel/Residence: Calling Card: Paris (France): Roger Horwitz. Printed. 187, boulevard Saint-Germain, Paris-VII. BAB. 08-79., n.d. / v.d.; 2 copies. (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Travel/Residence: Memorabilia: France (Paris): Papille (Les delices du Barbecue et toutes les autres! ..,)., n.d. / v.d.; Printed card. 2 items (different colors). (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Travel/Residence: Correspondence: France (Paris) [and elsewhere?]: Letters to Arthur Naiman., 1960-1967.; Photocopies. (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Travel/Residence: Correspondence: Letter to Paul Monette from Arthur Naiman., November 7, 1986.; 2 leaves. Typed (laser printer?), signed. (Box 41, Folder 8)
    From cover letter enclosing RH's letters: Roger and I first met in 1955 ....
  - Selective Service Status: Action(s) Taken: Draft Card: Letter from Jack Mendelsohn to RH., October 18, 1967.; Typed, signed. (Box 41, Folder 9)
    Enclosing draft card (to be burned?).
  - Travel: Documents: Passport, also Student Card, 1967-1983 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Residence: Journal: Boston: (?)., 1971; 1 vol., black bound. (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Portrait: RH in front of collage / painting (?). RH in dark suit and tie., seemingly early 1960s, n.d.; Black and white. (Box 36, Folder 15)
    Another copy with note from Donna Deitch that photo was taken at Harvard by her brother Dan? Deitch.
  - Residence: Journal: Boston: Summer vacation(?)., 1974.; Holograph entries in Square Deal Composition book. (Box 42, Folder 1)
    Corresponds to first meeting PM.
  - Residence: Photographs: Boston: Friends: RH, Rudy Kikel, Craig Rowland, and unidentified. (?)., 1974; 1 sheet contact prints. (Box 42, Folder 2)
    At beach (Provincetown?). Nude(s).
  - Residence: Photographs: Boston: Friends: RH, Rudy Kikel, Craig Rowland. (?)., 1974; 1 print (8 × 10). (Box 42, Folder 3)
    Printed from previous contact sheet. At beach. Nude(s).
  - Residence: Correspondences: Boston - Los Angeles (Kings Road): Letters from Madeleine Follain., ca. 1972-1986. (Box 42, Folder 4)
    See also letters to Paul Monette from Follain.
  - Residence: Correspondences: Boston (Chestnut Street): Postcards from E., 1977.; (2 postmarks) and 1 illegible. 3 items. (Box 42, Folder 5)
    E was perhaps a pet name for PM at the time.
  - Residence/Business: Calendars: Los Angeles:: Day by day. Social and business., 1980.; 1 bound vol. (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Residence/Business: Calendars: Los Angeles: Note-A-Date Daily. Also loose leaves from 1982. Leaves are not from 1982 volume described in next folder., 1981-1982.; 1 bound vol. (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Residence: Journal: Los Angeles: Few entries., 1982.; 1 vol., bound in black. (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Travel: Journal: Italy, October 1983.; Holograph entries in composition book (Clairefontaine). Entries on 4pp. only. (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Health: AIDS: Documents: Addendum consent form ... [Suranim testing]., August 9, 1985. (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Health: AIDS: Documents: Requesting no use of artificial means for prolonging life ..., September 18, 1986.; 1 leaf, signed by RH and witnesses. (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Legal: Estate: Documents: Last will and testament of Roger David Horwitz., 1986.; Copy. (Box 42, Folder 12)
    Original on file with Esther Richmond, attorney, Santa Monica, California.
  - Health: AIDS: Correspondences: Letter from Holly [Wright]., August 21, 1986.; 1 leaf. Typed, signed. (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Health: AIDS: Correspondences: Greeting card from Sally _____. (postmark)., August 11, 1986 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Health: AIDS: Correspondences: Letter in greeting card from Schneider family., October 6, 1986. (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Health: AIDS: Correspondences: Letter from Alice _____ (childhood friend)., March 17, 1986. (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Health: AIDS: Correspondences: Letter from Joey Terrill, The Center for the Partially Sighted., October 2, 1986. (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Photographs: Various Trips, Periods of Life, etc.: Some from before meeting PM, etc., n.d. / v.d.; Prints and copies of prints. (Box 42, Folder 18)
    Family photos, graduation, with PM and Madeleine Follain, etc.
  - Photograph: Roger's AIDS Quilt Panel: On display on the Ellipse in Washington D.C., n.d. / v.d. (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - Health: AIDS: Personal Effects: RDH's vampire teeth and last pair of glasses before his blindness. As per PM's note., n.d. / v.d. (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Juvenilia: Reflection: A publication of Senn High School, 5900 Glenwood Avenue, Chicago, Illinois. Co-editors: Roger Horwitz, editor-in-chief and Stephen Marcus, associate editor., 8pp. Mimeograph. (Box 43, Folder 2)
    Contains: editorial by RH and A Prosaic Elegy by RH.
  - Poetry: Various Drafts, 1961.; Holograph entries, drafts, etc. in Composition Book. (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Poetry: Various Drafts: Letter, Dear Mother and Dad as cover to typescript poems. (?)., 1962; All photocopies. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Poetry: Various Drafts, n.d. / v.d.; Holograph and typescript. Various versions (Box 43, Folder 5)
    cf. copies sent to parents.
  - Translation: The Promontory, by Henri Thomas: Drafts., n.d. / v.d.; Holograph and typescript. Seemingly several versions, none complete(?). (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Doctoral Thesis: The Novels of Henri Thomas: As submitted for partial requirements of the degree., May 1972.; 1 vol., bound in red buckram. (Box 43, Folder 7)
    Doctor of Philosophy in the subject of Comparative Literature. Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts.
  - Doctoral Thesis: The Novels of Henri Thomas: As submitted for partial requirements of the degree: Another copy., May 1972. (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Residence: Journal: Boston, 1966-1968 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Residence: Journal Loose Notes: Boston, 1966 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Residence: Correspondences: Boston: Joe to Roger, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Residence: Correspondences: Boston: Bob to Roger, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - Residence: Correspondences: Boston: Between Roger and Scotty, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - Residence: Correspondences: Boston: Roger to Roger, 1968 (Box 62, Folder 16)
  - Residence: Correspondences: Los Angeles, circa 1986 (Box 62, Folder 17)
  - Residence: Address Book: Los Angeles, circa 1985 (Box 62, Folder 18)
  - Estate, Roger Horwitz, 1979-1990 (Box 67, Folder 4)